

Daniëlle Duijst

Strategic UX & Product Researcher

Based in Malta | Open to remote



in linkedin.com/in/danielleduijst

SKILLS

Product Management

Product Strategy & Roadmapping Agile Methodologies (Scrum) Project Planning and Execution Risk Management Stakeholder Collaboration Opportunity Solution Tree Method

UX Research & Data Analysis

Qualitative/Quantitative Research Usability Testing

A/B Testing

Surveys

Analytics

Prototyping (Figma)

Design Thinking

Interaction Design

Information Architecture

Leadership Skills

Effective Communication

Presentation Skills

Workshop Facilitation

Problem-solving

Strategic Thinking

Customer-Centric Mindset

Technical Skills & Tools

HTML/CSS

Git

JavaScript

Automation (Zapier)

JIRA/Confluence

Google Analytics / Pendo

Airtable (Research Repository)

Sharepoint

Maze

Languages

Dutch (native)

English (fluent)

Maltese (basic)

Hi, I'm Daniëlle Duijst, a Strategic Product Researcher and UX Specialist with 7+ years of experience. I've led numerous research initiatives, consistently enhancing user satisfaction and product value. My unique blend of research, design, and technical skills, along with my ability to align stakeholders, positions me to excel in product management roles.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Strategic UX & Product Researcher

Covantis | Remote (based in Malta)

November 2022 - Present

- Leading 7 exploratory and strategic B2B research initiatives, facilitating research kickoff and debrief sessions with 10+ stakeholders and development teams.
- Conducting in-depth interviews with 80+ clients across 7 markets and 6 user personas, achieving at least 90% confidence level in understanding client needs per research initiative.
- Creating multiple Opportunity Solution Tree maps, communicating 16+ actionable findings to PMs, directly shaping product strategy.
- Conducting 30+ continuous discovery sessions, uncovering 15 new foundational topics.
- Implementing new UX metrics, increasing NPS from +5 to +15 and UMUX-L score from 65 to 68. Increased survey respondents from 93 to 170 in one quarter.
- Proposing and organizing a UXR maturity workshop, resulting in 7 initiatives to increase maturity and 5 initiatives to improve research ops.

UX Researcher (Quantitative & Qualitative)

BLEXR | Hybrid (based in Malta)

May 2020 - November 2022

- Leading 60+ qualitative and quantitative B2C research activities including around 100 sessions collecting more than 300 unique feedback items.
- Improving research accessibility and discoverability by 80% with a Research Repository created from scratch using Airtable.
- Developing 6 detailed, data-driven user personas by triangulating quantitative and qualitative research data.
- Delivering 10+ research presentations and reports, increasing stakeholder satisfaction.
- Redesigning the user recruitment flow, reducing time by 25% and growing the User Panel from 0 to 100+ users.

UX Designer & Researcher

ABN AMRO through NAVARA | Amsterdam

Apr 2019 - Apr 2020

- Leading UX Design & Research for 3+ employee apps (e.g. Sustainability App).
- Conducting concept and usability testing sessions with 30+ employees.
- Creating 5+ high-fidelity prototypes to gather user feedback and increase development efficiency.
- Facilitating 2 Design Thinking workshops with 10+ participants, including internal stakeholders and end-users, resulting in increased user value and satisfaction.

UX Consultant / Front-end Developer

ABN AMRO through Capgemini | Amsterdam

Mar 2018 - Apr 2019

- Delivering 20+ responsive front-end components, being aligned with a corporate design system.
- Conducting 15+ usability tests for the commercial website of ABN AMRO.
- Sharing knowledge from a conference visit about innovation in e-commerce.

UX Developer

Blue Harvest through Capgemini | Amsterdam

Feb 2018 - Mar 2018

- Identifying 10+ UX recommendations and processed improvements for the MVP.
- Collaborating within an international team of 5 people across 2 different time zones.
- Developing 10+ standard Angular components through self-study.

Awards

T500 TNW Talent under 25 shortlist 2018

T500 TNW Talent under 25 shortlist 2017

Publications

"What is the effect of personalization on the UX of Chatbots?", UX Collective, 2020

References

Santiago Fernandez and Lennart Overkamp (Covantis)

--

Gabriella Hinrichsen (BLEXR)

--

Bert de Groot (ABN AMRO)

--

Mattijs Ghijssen

(Navara)

--

Wouter Slager (Capgemini)

(Cap

Stefan Scerri (Tipico) **UX Researcher**

ETPA | Amsterdam

Jan 2018 - Feb 2018

- Conducting 5+ expert interviews.
- Assessing the platform using heuristic evaluation.
- Presenting recommendations to management of which 80% got implemented.

IT Talent Trainee

ABN AMRO through Procam | Amsterdam

Sep 2017 - Jan 2018

- Gathering 30+ requirements from stakeholders, writing 20+ user stories
- Designing an intranet page and logos for the team increasing team visibility.

Graduate Research Intern UX & Chatbots

Capgemini | Utrecht

Apr 2017 - Jul 2017

- Mixed method approach, qualitative research with 20 people and 121 survey respondents.
- Presenting the results of the research for more than 30 IT professionals
- Achieving high interest in the academic world with over 37.000 reads on Researchgate

Trainee Product Management

Tipico | Malta

Mar 2016 - Aug 2016

- Conducting over 10 user research activities and user tests
- Analysing user data from Google Analytics and UsabilityHub
- Presenting actionable findings to product managers, UX designers and business analysts.

Research Intern UX/UI

Bright Alley | Utrecht

Sep 2015 - Feb 2016

- Researching how to improve the UI/UX of a knowledge-sharing application
- By doing interviews, observations and delivering a report of UX/UI recommendations

Webdeveloper

Social Brothers | Utrecht

Jun 2015 - Sep 2015

• Delivering responsive and user-friendly websites by using PHP, HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

EDUCATION

M.Sc. Information Studies (Human-Centered Multimedia)

University of Amsterdam | 2016 - 2017

Minor Digital Design & Psychology

University of Malta | 2014 - 2015

B.Sc. Information Studies

University of Utrecht | 2012 - 2016

CERTIFICATES

UX Management: Strategy & Tactics

The IDF | July 2021

User Research Methods

The IDF | June 2021

Opportunity Mapping

Product Talk | March 2021

Fundamentals of Digital Marketing

Google | Dec 2018

Customer Journey Design

Capgemini | Nov 2018

Professional Scrum Master I

Scrum.org | May 2018